Chapter 121. Midnight. The folks bullwarks.
Stub and flask mounted on them and passing additional lashings over the anchors there hanging.
No, Stub. You may pound that knot there as much as you please, but you will
never pound into me what you were just now saying. And how long ago is it since
you said the very contrary? Didn't you once say that whatever ship Ahab sails
in, that ship should pay something extra on its insurance policy, just as though
it were loaded with powder barrels aft and boxes of Lucifers forward? Stop now.
Didn't you say so? Well, suppose I did.
What then? I've part changed my flesh since that time. Why not my mind?
Besides, supposing we are loaded with powder barrels aft and Lucifer's
forward. How the devil should the Lucifers get a fire in this drenching
spray here? Why, my little man? You have pretty red hair, but you couldn't get a
fire now. Shake yourself. Your Aquarius or the water barrier flask might fill
pictures at your coat collar. Don't you see then that for these extra risks the
marine insurance companies have extra guarantees? Here are hydrants flask. But
hark again and I'll answer you the other thing. First take your leg off from the
crown of the anchor here though so I can pass the rope. Now listen. What's the
mighty difference between holding a mass lightning rod in the storm and standing
close by a mass that hasn't got any lightning rod at all in a storm? Don't
you see, you timberhead, that no harm can come to the holder of the rod,
unless the mast is first struck? What are you talking about then? Not one ship
in a hundred carries rods, and Ahab, I, man, and all of us were in no more
danger then, in my poor opinion, than all the crews in 10,000 ships now
sailing the seas. Why you, King Post?
You, I suppose, would have every man in the world go about with a small
lightning rod running up the corner of his hat, like a militia officer's
skewered feather, and trailing behind like a sash. Why don't you be sensible,
Flask? It's easy to be sensible. Why don't you then? Any man with half an eye
can be sensible.
I don't know that, Stub. You sometimes find it rather hard. Yes, when a
fellow's soaked through, it's hard to be sensible. That's a fact. And I am about
drenched with this spray. Never mind.
Catch the turn there and pass. It seems to me we are lashing down these anchors
now as if they were never going to be used again. Tying these two anchors here
at last. Seems like tying a man's hands behind him. And what big, generous hands
they are, to be sure. These are your iron fists, eh? What a hold they have,
too. I wonder. flask whether the world is anchored anywhere. If she is, she
swings with an uncommon long cable, though. There, hammer that knot down and
we're done. So, next to touching land, lighting on deck is most satisfactory, I
say. Just ring out my jacket skirts, will you? Thank you. They laugh at long
toss so fast, but it seems to me a long-tailed coat ought always to be worn
in storms of float. The tails tapering down that way serve to carry off the
water, do you see? Same with cocked hats. The form gable end eve
troughs flasks. No more monkey jackets and tarpolins for me. I must mount a
swallow tail and drive down a beaver. So hello, there goes my tarpolin overboard. Lord,
lord that the winds that come from heaven should be so unmannerly.
This is a nasty night, lad.